{
"records":[
{"Question":"A Member of Parliament from Montreal announces that she will spend her weekend in her electoral district. This means she would be:", "Answer":"In the part of Montreal where she was elected", "A":"In her office on Parliament Hill", "B":"Visiting the province of Quebec", "C":"In the part of Montreal where she was elected", "D":"Going on a vacation"},
{"Question":"After a federal election, which party forms the new government?", "Answer":"The party with the most elected representatives is invited by the Governor General to become the party in power.", "A":"The party with the most elected representatives is invited by the Governor General to become the party in power.", "B":"The Queen herself picks any party to run the government.", "C":"The Governor General proposes a law for elected officials to become the governing body.", "D":"The Premiers of each province pick a party to run the government"},
{"Question":"Approximately how many Canadians served in the First World War?", "Answer":"More than 600,000.", "A":"7000.", "B":"8 million.", "C":"About 60,000.", "D":"More than 600,000."},
{"Question":"Canada has three territories and how many provinces?", "Answer":"10", "A":"13", "B":"10", "C":"3", "D":"5"},
{"Question":"Fatima is a new immigrant in Canada. What law allows her to take up a job at par with a man?", "Answer":"Equality of women and men", "A":"Equality of women and men", "B":"Equality of all races.", "C":"Equal pay for equal work.", "D":"Equal rights."},
{"Question":"From where does the name Canada come from?", "Answer":"From Kanata, the Huron-Iroquois word for village.", "A":"From the Inuit word meaning country.", "B":"From the French word meaning joining.", "C":"From the Metis word meaning rivers.", "D":"From Kanata, the Huron-Iroquois word for village."},
{"Question":"Give an example of how you can show responsibility by participating in your community.", "Answer":"Volunteer", "A":"Mind your own business.", "B":"Have a party.", "C":"Keep your property tidy.", "D":"Volunteer"},
{"Question":"Give an example of where English and French have equal status in Canada.", "Answer":"In the Parliament of Canada.", "A":"In schools.", "B":"In the workplace.", "C":"In the Parliament of Canada.", "D":"At City Hall."},
{"Question":"Give the first two lines of Canada's national anthem?", "Answer":"O Canada! Our home and native land! True patriot love in all thy sons command.", "A":"O Canada! Our home and native land! True patriot love in all thy sons command.", "B":"O Canada! Our province and native land! True patriot love in all thy sons command.", "C":"O Canada! From far and wide, O Canada, We stand on guard for thee.", "D":"O Canada! We stand on guard for thee."},
{"Question":"How are Members of Parliament chosen?", "Answer":"Elected by Canadian citizens.", "A":"Appointed by the Prime Minister.", "B":"Elected by Canadian citizens.", "C":"Appointed by the Queen.", "D":"Elected by the Provincial Ministers."},
{"Question":"How are Senators chosen?", "Answer":"Senators are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister.", "A":"By the Governor General of Canada.", "B":"By the Premiers of all provinces.", "C":"Appointed by the Queen.", "D":"Senators are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister."},
{"Question":"How does a bill become a law?", "Answer":"Approval by a majority in the House of Commons and Senate and finally the Governor General.", "A":"The Lieutenant Governor must approve the bill.", "B":"Approval by a majority in the House of Commons and Senate and finally the Governor General.", "C":"The Queen must sign the bill.", "D":"Approval by the Members of the Legislative Assembly."},
{"Question":"How is a Cabinet Minister chosen?", "Answer":"By the Prime Minister", "A":"By the Queen.", "B":"By the voters.", "C":"By other Cabinet Ministers.", "D":"By the Prime Minister"},
{"Question":"How is the government formed after a federal election?", "Answer":"The party with the most elected representatives becomes the party in power. The leader of this party becomes the Prime Minister.", "A":"The party with the most elected representatives becomes the party in power. The Queen chooses the Prime Minister from this party", "B":"The party with the most elected representatives becomes the party in power. The leader of this party becomes the Prime Minister.", "C":"The Governor General picks a party and a Prime Minister to run the government.", "D":"Each province elects one representative to form the government. The Queen then chooses the Prime Minister."},
{"Question":"How is the Prime Minister chosen?", "Answer":"The leader of the party with the most elected representatives becomes the Prime Minister.", "A":"The Queen appoints the Prime Minister.", "B":"The Governor General with the Senate appoint the Prime Minister", "C":"The leader of the party with the most elected representatives becomes the Prime Minister.", "D":"The MPs vote on the Prime Minister."},
{"Question":"In Canada's justice system what does presumption of innocence mean?", "Answer":"Everyone is innocent until proven guilty", "A":"Everyone is guilty until proven innocent", "B":"Guilt is decided by public opinion", "C":"Innocence is decided by public opinion", "D":"Everyone is innocent until proven guilty"},
{"Question":"In the 1960s, Quebec experienced an era of rapid change. What is this called?", "Answer":"The Quiet Revolution.", "A":"The West Movement.", "B":"The Revolution.", "C":"The Quiet Revolution.", "D":"La Francophonie."},
{"Question":"In what industry do most Canadians work?", "Answer":"Service.", "A":"Natural resources", "B":"Tourism.", "C":"Service.", "D":"Manufacturing."},
{"Question":"Name three additional rights protected by the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms", "Answer":"Mobility rights, Multiculturalism, and Aboriginal Peoples' rights", "A":"Freedom of speech, Right to own land, and Right to a fair trial.", "B":"Mobility rights, Multiculturalism, and Aboriginal Peoples' rights", "C":"Right to ski anywhere in Canada, Moving rights, and Right to public assembly.", "D":"Right to vote, Right to speak publicly, and Security rights."},
{"Question":"Name two fundamental freedoms protected by the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms.", "Answer":"Freedom of conscience and religion, and Freedom of association.", "A":"Freedom of conscience and religion, and Freedom of association.", "B":"Equality rights, and to care for Canada's heritage.", "C":"Basic freedoms, and obeying laws.", "D":"Aboriginal peoples' rights, and to volunteer."},
{"Question":"Name two responsibilities of the federal government.", "Answer":"National defence and foreign policy.", "A":"National defence and firefighting.", "B":"National defence and foreign policy.", "C":"Citizenship and highways.", "D":"Recycling and education."},
{"Question":"Name two responsibilities of the provincial and territorial government.", "Answer":"Health and Education", "A":"Citizenship and Foreign Policy", "B":"Health and Education", "C":"Defense and Currency", "D":"Criminal Law and Interprovincial Trade"},
{"Question":"On what date did Nunavut become a territory?", "Answer":"April 1st, 1999", "A":"July 1st, 1867", "B":"April 1st, 1999", "C":"June 24th, 1995", "D":"March 31st, 1949"},
{"Question":"One third of all Canadians live in which province?", "Answer":"Ontario.", "A":"Quebec.", "B":"Ontario.", "C":"Northwest Territories.", "D":"Manitoba."},
{"Question":"What are the Prairie provinces and their capital cities?", "Answer":"Alberta (Edmonton), Saskatchewan (Regina) and Manitoba (Winnipeg)", "A":"Alberta (Edmonton) and Saskatchewan (Regina).", "B":"Alberta (Edmonton), Saskatchewan (Regina) and Manitoba (Winnipeg)", "C":"Saskatchewan (Regina) and Manitoba (Winnipeg).", "D":"Saskatchewan (Regina), Manitoba (Winnipeg) and Ontario (Toronto)."},
{"Question":"What are the provinces of Central Canada and their capital cities?", "Answer":"Ontario (Toronto) and Quebec (Quebec City).", "A":"Manitoba (Winnipeg) and Ontario (Toronto).", "B":"Quebec (Quebec City) and Prince Edward Island (Charlottetown).", "C":"Ontario (Toronto) and Quebec (Quebec City).", "D":"Saskatchewan (Regina) and Manitoba Winnipeg)."},
{"Question":"What are the territories of Northern Canada and their capital cities?", "Answer":"Yukon Territory (Whitehorse), Northwest Territories (Yellowknife), and Nunavut (Iqaluit).", "A":"Alaska (Juneau) and Yukon Territory (Whitehorse).", "B":"Northwest Territories (Yellowknife) and Alaska (Juneau).", "C":"Northwest Territories (Yellowknife).", "D":"Yukon Territory (Whitehorse), Northwest Territories (Yellowknife), and Nunavut (Iqaluit)."},
{"Question":"What are the three main groups of Aboriginal peoples?", "Answer":"First Nations, Metis and Inuit.", "A":"First Nations, Metis and Inuit.", "B":"Acadians, Metis and Inuit.", "C":"United Empire Loyalists, Metis and Inuit.", "D":"Inuit, Metis and Acadians."},
{"Question":"What are the three main types of industry in Canada?", "Answer":"Natural resources, manufacturing and services.", "A":"Natural resources, tourism and service industries.", "B":"Tourism, services and manufacturing.", "C":"Natural resources, tourism and manufacturing.", "D":"Natural resources, manufacturing and services."},
{"Question":"What are the three parts of Parliament?", "Answer":"The Queen, the House of Commons and the Senate.", "A":"The Sovereign, Governor General and Prime Minister.", "B":"The House of Commons, the Legislative Assembly and the Senate.", "C":"The Queen, the Legislative Assembly and the Senate.", "D":"The Queen, the House of Commons and the Senate."},
{"Question":"What do you call a law before it is passed?", "Answer":"A Bill.", "A":"A New law.", "B":"A Proposed law.", "C":"A Bill.", "D":"A New proposal."},
{"Question":"What do you call the Sovereign's representative in the provinces?", "Answer":"Lieutenant-Governor.", "A":"Premier.", "B":"Member of the Legislative Assembly.", "C":"Lieutenant-Governor.", "D":"Senator."},
{"Question":"What does Confederation mean?", "Answer":"Joining of provinces to make a new country.", "A":"The United States Confederate soldiers came to Canada.", "B":"Joining of communities to become a province.", "C":"Joining of suburbs to form a large city.", "D":"Joining of provinces to make a new country."},
{"Question":"What happened at the Battle of the Plains of Abraham?", "Answer":"The British defeated the French marking the end of France's empire in America", "A":"The Voyagers battled with the British for fur trading rights", "B":"Americans fought the United Empire Loyalists during the American Revolution", "C":"The British defeated the French marking the end of France's empire in America", "D":"The French defeated the British in a battle for Quebec"},
{"Question":"What is a major river in Quebec?", "Answer":"St. Lawrence River", "A":"Fraser River", "B":"St. Lawrence River", "C":"Niagara", "D":"Hudson's Bay."},
{"Question":"What is the capital city of Ontario?", "Answer":"Toronto", "A":"Kingston", "B":"Ottawa", "C":"Toronto", "D":"London"},
{"Question":"What is the capital city of Canada?", "Answer":"Ottawa", "A":"Ottawa", "B":"Toronto.", "C":"Montreal.", "D":"Hull."},
{"Question":"What is the government of all of Canada called?", "Answer":"Federal.", "A":"National assembly.", "B":"Legislature.", "C":"Federal.", "D":"Council."},
{"Question":"What is the highest court in Canada?", "Answer":"The Supreme Court of Canada", "A":"The Queen's Court", "B":"The Senate Court of Canada", "C":"The Supreme Court of Canada", "D":"The Crown Court of Canada"},
{"Question":"What is the highest military honour a Canadian can receive?", "Answer":"Victoria Cross.", "A":"Purple Cross.", "B":"Badge of Courage.", "C":"Order of Merit.", "D":"Victoria Cross."},
{"Question":"What is the largest religious affiliation in Canada?", "Answer":"Catholic.", "A":"Catholic.", "B":"Muslim.", "C":"Jewish", "D":"Hindu."},
{"Question":"What is the meaning of the Remembrance Day poppy?", "Answer":"To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day.", "A":"To remember our Sovereign, Queen Elizabeth II.", "B":"To celebrate Confederation.", "C":"To honour Prime Ministers who have died.", "D":"To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day."},
{"Question":"What three oceans border Canada?", "Answer":"Atlantic, Arctic and Pacific.", "A":"Atlantic, Arctic and Bering.", "B":"Atlantic, Arctic and Pacific.", "C":"Pacific, Indian and Atlantic.", "D":"Hudson, Pacific and Atlantic."},
{"Question":"What was the Underground Railroad?", "Answer":"An anti-slavery network that helped thousands of slaves escape the United States and settle in Canada", "A":"An anti-slavery network that helped thousands of slaves escape the United States and settle in Canada", "B":"A railroad through the Rockies that was mainly through mountain tunnels", "C":"A network fur traders used to transport beaver pelts to the United States", "D":"The first underground subway tunnel in Toronto"},
{"Question":"What year did Newfoundland and Labrador join Canada?", "Answer":"1949", "A":"1867", "B":"1955", "C":"1949", "D":"1880"},
{"Question":"When asked, who must you tell how you voted in a federal election?", "Answer":"No one.", "A":"Your employer.", "B":"No one.", "C":"A police officer.", "D":"An Elections Canada official."},
{"Question":"When did the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms become part of the Canadian Constitution?", "Answer":"1982.", "A":"1867.", "B":"1905.", "C":"1982.", "D":"1878."},
{"Question":"When is Remembrance Day celebrated?", "Answer":"November 11th.", "A":"July 1st.", "B":"October 1st.", "C":"November 11th.", "D":"December 25th."},
{"Question":"Where are the Great Lakes?", "Answer":"Between Ontario and the United States.", "A":"Between Ontario and the United States.", "B":"Manitoba.", "C":"Northern Quebec.", "D":"Atlantic Canada."},
{"Question":"Where are the Parliament Buildings located?", "Answer":"Ottawa.", "A":"Ottawa.", "B":"Quebec City.", "C":"Hull.", "D":"Toronto."},
{"Question":"Where does Canada rank in the world's largest countries?", "Answer":"Second", "A":"First", "B":"Second", "C":"Third", "D":"Fourth"},
{"Question":"Which animal is an official symbol of Canada?", "Answer":"The beaver.", "A":"The moose.", "B":"The hawk.", "C":"The beaver.", "D":"The deer."},
{"Question":"Which of the following is NOT a feature of Canada's system of government?", "Answer":"Dictatorship.", "A":"A federal state.", "B":"Parliamentary democracy.", "C":"Constitutional Monarchy.", "D":"Dictatorship."},
{"Question":"Which of the following sentences best describes the War of 1812?", "Answer":"The USA invaded Canada and was defeated, which ensured that Canada would remain independent of the United States.", "A":"Napoleon's fleet was defeated by the Royal Navy in the war.", "B":"The USA became independent from the British Empire after the war.", "C":"The USA invaded Canada and was defeated, which ensured that Canada would remain independent of the United States.", "D":"Canada joined the United States after the war."},
{"Question":"Which port is the largest and busiest in Canada?", "Answer":"The Port of Vancouver", "A":"The Port of Halifax", "B":"The Port of Montreal", "C":"The Port of Vancouver", "D":"The Port of Victoria"},
{"Question":"Which province has its own time zone?", "Answer":"Newfoundland and Labrador", "A":"British Columbia", "B":"Newfoundland and Labrador", "C":"Nunavut", "D":"Nova Scotia"},
{"Question":"Which province in Canada is the smallest in land size?", "Answer":"Prince Edward Island.", "A":"Nova Scotia.", "B":"Prince Edward Island.", "C":"Yukon Territory.", "D":"Newfoundland and Labrador."},
{"Question":"Which region covers more than one-third of Canada?", "Answer":"Northern Territories.", "A":"Central Canada.", "B":"Prairies.", "C":"Atlantic Canada.", "D":"Northern Territories."},
{"Question":"Which was the last province to join Canada?", "Answer":"Newfoundland.", "A":"Newfoundland.", "B":"Alberta.", "C":"Saskatchewan.", "D":"British Columbia."},
{"Question":"Who are the Aboriginal peoples of Canada?", "Answer":"The first people to live in Canada", "A":"The first European settlers to arrive in Canada", "B":"The descendents of the first Australian immigrants to Canada", "C":"The first people to live in Canada", "D":"The first settlers of Newfoundland"},
{"Question":"Who are the Acadians?", "Answer":"The descendants of French colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604.", "A":"Aboriginal people of the arctic.", "B":"French-speaking Catholics living in Ontario.", "C":"The descendants of French colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604.", "D":"English speaking refugees who settled in Louisiana."},
{"Question":"Who do Members of Parliament represent?", "Answer":"Everyone who lives in his or her electoral district.", "A":"All of the Canadians living in the north.", "B":"Only Canadians living in Central Canada.", "C":"Everyone who lives in his or her electoral district.", "D":"Canadians living in the province in which he/she was elected."},
{"Question":"Who had played an important part in building the Canadian Pacific Railway (CPR)?", "Answer":"Chinese railroad workers.", "A":"American railroad engineers.", "B":"Acadian railroad workers.", "C":"Chinese railroad workers.", "D":"Afro-American slaves."},
{"Question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?", "Answer":"Sir John A. Macdonald", "A":"Louis Riel", "B":"Sir John A. Macdonald", "C":"Lester B. Pearson", "D":"Abraham Lincoln"},
{"Question":"Who is Canada's Head of State?", "Answer":"Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II.", "A":"Governor General of Canada.", "B":"Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II.", "C":"Prime Minister.", "D":"Lieutenant Governor."}
]
} 
  